https://www.scbc.org.uk/privacy/

Privacy Policy
The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a the new EU privacy law that comes into force on 25th May 2018. It affects every charity and organisation using personal data. This law affects all UK citizens regardless of the outcome of Brexit negotiations.
We at Sutton Coldfield Baptist Church take our responsibilities seriously and want to ensure that your personal data and communication preferences are adhered to.
This page contains our privacy notices and other information that you will be of value to you.
1. Privacy Notice for Collecting Information from Church Members and Attendees
2. Privacy Notice for collecting information about children /young people attending an activity
3. Privacy Notice for requesting details from a new (or potential) employee
4. Website Privacy Policy (Opens in a new tab)
Privacy Notice for collecting information from church members and attendees.
Under Data Protection legislation the church Charity Trustees of Sutton Coldfield Baptist Church are the Data Controller and the Administration Team Leader acts as our Data Protection Officer.
We are collecting this information to enable the church to keep in touch with you and provide pastoral support as appropriate. Data Protection legislation allows us to process this information as we regard it as being in the church’s legitimate interest.
Your name and contact details will be entered into our church Management Information System which is which is password protected and accessed only by the Church Staff and Leaders. Your contact details will be removed from the database once you are no longer involved in activities of the church – unless you ask to remain on our archive of our “church friends”.
We do not produce a directory of church members and attendees for circulation. Rather we invite all those on our database to access “MyChurchSuite”. All those on our “Church Suite” database can see your name by default, but not other details unless you change you privacy levels to select which of your contact details are visible. If you do not want your name to appear on MyChurchSuite, please notify the office.
We will not give your information to any other church member or attendee.
To enable us to provide adequate pastoral support to you and your family, one of the Team Leaders may record information that may be regarded as sensitive. This information will be stored (in password protected documents) on the church’s management information system but the password will only be known by the relevant Team Leader. This information will NOT be disclosed to anyone else without your consent.
You have the right to ask to see any information we hold about you (including the pastoral support information) by submitting a ‘Subject Access Request’ to the Administration Team Leader. You also have the right to ask for information that you believe to be incorrect to be rectified.
If you are concerned about the way your information is being handled please speak to our Data Protection Officer.
If you are still unhappy you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office.
Privacy Notice for collecting information about children /young people attending an activity
Under Data Protection legislation the church Charity Trustees of Sutton Coldfield Baptist Church are the Data Controller and the Administration Team Leader acts as our Data Protection Officer.
We are collecting this information to enable the church to run activities for children and young people safely, and to ensure we can contact you (or other nominated adult) in case of an emergency.
Data Protection legislation allows us to process this information as we regard it as being in the church’s legitimate interest. If you are unable to supply the information requested then we will be unable to accept your child at our activity.
The information your supply will be held on our church Management Information System which is password protected and may also be kept in paper form in a folder which will be kept in a securely locked cupboard in the church office when not in use for the activity. Only the church’s staff team and activity leaders will have access to this information.
The paper forms will be destroyed and electronic data deleted once the child or young person is no longer involved in the church activities, unless you have ticked the box asking us to keep you informed about future activities we think your child/young person might be interested in attending. If this is the case we will retain your details for the sole purpose of notifying you of such events. We will NOT pass on this information to anyone else.
You have the right to ask to be removed from this circulation list at any time.
If you are concerned about the way your information is being handled please speak to our Data Protection Officer.
If you are still unhappy you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office.
Privacy Notice for requesting details from a new (or potential) employee
Under Data Protection legislation the church Charity Trustees of Sutton Coldfield Baptist Church are the Data Controller and the Administration Team Leader acts as our Data Protection Officer.
We are collecting this information to enable us to enter into a contract of employment with you. If you are unable to provide this information then we will be unable to enter into that contract.
The information you supply in this form will be
Held on an area of the church office management information system which is password protected and accessed only by the Team Leader and Administration Team Leader.
Destroyed six months after you leave our employment.
We will be undertaking performance appraisals as part of your employment and copies of the reports from these (along with all documents supplied as part of your application) will be kept in a password protected section of the church MIS which can only be accessed by the Team Leader, Administration Team and an other team leader if they are your Line Manager. If appropriate, information from these documents may be shared with other charity Trustees but will NOT be shared with anyone else without your consent.
You have the right to ask to see any information we hold about you by submitting a ‘Subject Access Request’ to the Administration Team Leader. You also have the right to ask for information which you believe to be incorrect to be rectified.
If you are concerned about the way your information is being handled please speak to our Data Protection Officer.
If you are still unhappy you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office.
Get In Touch
Your Name
Email Address
Telephone
Area of interest
---LivestreamAll aboardCafeChurchQuestions of LifeFood bankOther (please state)
How can we help?
Please leave this field empty.
Latest Posts
11th December 10th December 9th December 8th December
Devotional Videos Search
Search for:
Office Hours:
8.30am - 3pm
Safeguarding
Privacy Policy
Website Privacy/Cookies
Sitemap
Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
YouTube
Soundcloud
© 2020 Sutton Coldfield Baptist Church.
All Rights Reserved.
Our site uses cookies, which helps us to improve our site and enables us to deliver the best possible service and customer experience. By clicking Accept, you are agreeing to our cookie policy. AcceptPrivacy Policy
